Francisco Pablo Flores Taipe

Nationality: Ecuadorian Date of birth: 27/05/1987 Phone number: (+49) 17624861016

■ Email address: franciscopabloflores@gmail.com **⊕ Website:** www.fflorestaipe.com

• Work: Mönchebergstraße 17, Kassel, 34109 Kassel (Germany)

ABOUT ME

Research interests: (behavioral) development economics, economics of inequality, economics of education, gender economics.

<u>Teaching load</u>: Behavioral Economics of Poverty, Economics of Entrepreneurship (with Guido Bünstorf), (Quasi-) Experiments in Entrepreneurship Research (with Guido Bünstorf and Maria Mavlikeva), Field Experiments (Tutorial)

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Doctoral student in Economics

University of Kassel [14/05/2018 - Current]

Master of Science in Economic Behavior and Governance

University of Kassel [04/2016 – 04/2018]

Address: Kassel (Germany)

Thesis: Showing Life Opportunities: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through online courses in schools. (Supervisor: Dr. Igor Asanov)

Bachelor of Science in Economics

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Ecuador (PUCE) [10/2005 – 12/2011]

Address: Quito (Ecuador)

Thesis: El sector eléctrico ecuatoriano en los últimos 20 años: estrategias para alcanzar la seguridad energética

(Supervisor: MSc. Rubén Flores)

PUBLICATIONS

Remote-learning, time-use, and mental health of Ecuadorian high-school students during the COVID-19 quarantine

[2021]

Asanov, Igor, Francisco Flores, David McKenzie, Mona Mensmann, and Mathis Schulte. "Remote-learning, time-use, and mental health of Ecuadorian high-school students during the COVID-19 quarantine." *World development* 138 (2021): 105225.

Inspiring the way to a better future: The effect of role models on reshaping the academic ambitions of disadvantaged students.

[2022]

Francisco Flores. "Inspiring the way to a better future: The effect of role models on reshaping the academic ambitions of disadvantaged students." Working Paper.

Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[2022]

Asanov, Igor, Atstebro, Thomas; Buenstorf, Guido; Creponm Brunó, Francisco Flores, David McKenzie, Mona Mensmann, and Mathis Schulte. "Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students" Working Paper.

System-, Teacher-, and Student-level Interventions for Improving Participation in Online Learning at Scale in High Schools

[2022]

Asanov, Igor, Asanov (Noha), Anastasyia, Atstebro, Thomas; Buenstorf, Guido; Creponm Brunó, Francisco Flores, David McKenzie, Mona Mensmann, and Mathis Schulte. "System-, Teacher-, and Student-level Interventions for Improving Participation in Online Learning at Scale in High Schools." Working Paper.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Grant secured: SIEF's COVID-19 Emergency Window

The World Bank Group [06/2020]

Project: <u>Transitioning from In-School to At-Home Virtual Learning in High Schools</u>: Lessons from Ecuador during the Covid-19 shutdown

Path to Scale Award

Innovation for Poverty Action (IPA) [11/2019]

Project: <u>Showing Life Opportunities</u>: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through online courses in schools

Grant secured: IGL Grants Program

Innovation Growth Lab (IGL) [03/2018]

Project: <u>Showing Life Opportunities</u>: Increasing opportunity-driven entrepreneurship and STEM careers through online courses in schools

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

Inspiring the way to a better future: The effect of role models on reshaping the academic ambitions of disadvantaged students.

[Online, 11/11/2022]

Flores, F. "Inspiring the way to a better future: The effect of role models on reshaping the academic ambitions of disadvantaged students." <u>AEFP workshop</u>: Junior Scholars and the Job Market. November 11th, online.

Aspirations, Poverty and Education: Can a role model intervention mitigate the consequences of deprivation? Lessons from Ecuador

[University of Bologna, 31/08/2022 – 03/09/2022]

Flores, F.: Aspirations, Poverty and Education: Can a role model intervention mitigate the consequences of deprivation? Lessons from Ecuador. <u>ESA European Meeting</u>. September 3rd, Bologna (Italy).

Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[Universidad San Francisco de Quito (USFQ), 04/07/2022 – 07/07/2022]

Flores, F.: Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students. Experimental Economics Conference 2022 (USFQ). July 7th, Galapagos (Ecuador). (Co-authors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Sloan School of Management (MIT), 13/06/2022 – 16/06/2022]

Flores, F.: Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students. <u>ESA World Meeting</u>. June 15th, Boston (USA). (Co-authors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[University of Chicago, 08/06/2022 – 09/06/2022]

Flores, F.: Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students. <u>Advance in Field Experiments Meeting (AFE)</u>. June 9th, Chicago (USA). (Co-authors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students

[University of Copenhagen, 29/03/2022 - 29/03/2022]

Flores, F.: Effects of a Role Models Intervention on Promoting STEM and Entrepreneurship Activities among High School Students. <u>Copenhagen Education Network Workshop (CEN)</u>. March 29th, Copenhagen (Denmark). (Coauthors: Asanov I., Astebro T., Bünstorf G., Crépon B., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

Impacts of Personal Initiative and Negotiations Training on Remote-Learning, Time-Use, and Mental Health of Ecuadorian High-School Students during the COVID-19 Quarantine

[Virtual, 10/09/2020 - 12/09/2020]

Flores, F.: Impacts of Personal Initiative and Negotiations Training on Remote-Learning, Time-Use, and Mental Health of Ecuadorian High-School Students during the COVID-19 Quarantine. <u>ESA World Meeting</u>. September 11th, Virtual. (Co-authors: Asanov I., McKenzie D., Mensmann M., Schulte M.)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Researcher and lecturer at the Faculty of Economics (FB-07)

University of Kassel [14/05/2018 - Current]

City: Kassel

Country: Germany

Research fields: economics of education, development economics, gender economics, behavioral economics, experimental economics.

Teach courses on:

- · Behavioral Economics of Poverty
- Economics of Entrepreneurship
- (Quasi-) Experiments in Entrepreneurship Research
- Field Experiments (Tutorial)
- Intellectual Property Rights (Tutorial)

Short-term Consultant

The World Bank Group [15/07/2020 - 31/10/2020]

City: Kassel

Country: Germany

Key tasks:

- Setting the field to expand an online educational program nationwide
- Monitoring a team that supports students and teachers while interacting with online solutions
- Solving issues associated with working with new technologies, particularly in remote areas.

Short-term Consultant

The World Bank Group [23/05/2019 – 31/08/2019]

City: Kassel

Country: Germany

Key tasks:

- Piloting an online intervention designed to train high school students at scale.
- Testing the performance of online education in remote areas

- Training teachers and administrative personnel on the dynamics of working with online solutions at scale.
- Monitoring rapid-fire data collection using phone-based tools.
- It includes dealing with protocols to mitigate the COVID-19 emergency.

Research Assistant at the Economi Policy, Entrepreneurships and Innovation Unit (EPIE) *University of Kassel* [02/2017 – 04/2018]

City: Kassel

Country: Germany

- Research fields: record linkages, economics of innovation
- Key tasks: literature review, data cleaning, compilation, and preparation.

Senior consultant at the Quantitative Research Center for Economic and Social Development *Quantitative Research Center for Economic and Social Development (Economica-CIC)* [04/2014 – 09/2015]

City: Quito

Country: Ecuador

Research fields: health economics, economics of education, gender economics, environmental economics Key tasks:

- Literature review, data analysis, and drafting of policy notes for decision-makers in Ecuador (i.e., the Ministry of Education, National Secretary of Planning)
- Evaluation of multi-media educative solutions to improve students' situation at scale (qualitative and quantitative assessment).
- Dissemination of research results among policymakers and the general audience.
- · Capacity-building in team activities.

NETWORKS AND MEMBERSHIPS

Innovation for Poverty Action

[Global, 05/2020 – Current]

Link: https://www.poverty-action.org/people/francisco-flores

International Center for Higher Education Research (INCHER)

[Kassel, Germany, 05/2019 - Current]

Link: https://www.uni-kassel.de/forschung/en/27/incher/people/flores-francisco

Economics Science Association

[Global, 05/2018 - Current]

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **Spanish**

Other language(s):

English German

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING B2 LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Programming and Typesetting (Matlab, Python, STATA, R, SQL, Aimms, LATEX) / Microsoft Office / Social Media